Seungyun Todd Oh

email: toddstonefieldoh@gmail.com | phone: 917-609-9314 | website: toddstonefieldoh.com | location: New York, NY

Overview

I'm a UI/X engineer formerly a product lead. Over the years, I've focused on delivering a great user experience in areas including financial services and data analytics. With my expertise, I always find the right way to build great user experience and interface with best engineering practices.

Skills

Front-end — JavaScript/TypeScript, React.js, Redux, Web Workers, CSS3, Unit testing

UX/UI Design — Figma, UX wireframes, Prototyping, Customer UI research

Back-end — Node.js/Express, MySQL

Tools — Git, CI/CD (CircleCI, Jenkins), Sonarqube

Languages — English and Korean

Education

B.S. Sociology, 2018 Yonsei University, Seoul, South Korea

Additional Experiences

Intern, Ars Praxia — Helped a strategy consulting team perform data cleaning for a Semantic Network Analysis project. (Nov 2011-Feb 2012)

Samsung Electronics Super Rookie
Membership — An invite-only program
for students in STEM and Liberal Arts
(2012-2013)

TEDxYouth Seoul 2010 — Gave a speech about startup experience.

Experiences

Senior Web Engineer, CVS Health (Aetna)

Jul 2020 - Present | New York, NY

Analytics & Behavior Change — Campaign Production Launchpad (CPL) UX

- Leading CPL UI/UX focusing on usability, self-servicing, and scalability
- Established CPL UX Design System with its own design language,
 UX system guide/manifest and engineering documentation
- Custom-designed journey flow builder with auto-flow, autolayout, auto-correction and smart highlight— enabling a sophisticated processor functionality for regular non-technical users by abstracting and simplifying the interaction.
- Custom-designed UI data processing engine with dynamic schema templating, template object generation, instant configuration quality review/evaluation
- Custom-designed UI components and shared controllers

Software Engineer, Rally Rd. (RSE Markets, Inc.)

Oct 2019 - Jul 2020 | New York, NY

Focused on front-end engineering of the alternative asset investment service.

- Primary maintainer of the React web application and Android client codebase for its alternative asset investing experience
- Built a custom gesture-based carousel component for Web and Android for asset browsing experience

Product Lead/Founder, Toast Labs, LLC.

Apr 2015 - Jul 2017 | Palo Alto, CA/Seoul, South Korea

Led a technology startup that developed and launched mobile applications, including "#Newsrooms" application, which provided a solution for journalistic bias through an automatically generated news briefing.

- Custom-designed a custom interface framework for desktop and mobile experience in JavaScript.
- Built a Node.js/MongoDB backend running a number of RESTful API endpoints and a custom news natural language processing pipeline for "#Newsrooms".
- Analyzed application user metrics, executed data-driven product adjustments and redesign.
- Built an adaptive low-power geofence engine and camera scribble UX in Objective-C.